Saurabh Bansal



saurabh.uk18@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/bansal-saurabh



+44 7826 974749



https://bansal-saurabh.github.io/

Summary

Experienced Technical Consultant with a demonstrated history of working in the information technology and services industry. Skilled in the deployment of traditional as well as modern software solutions on a wide variety of infrastructure. Freelance developer with a solid understanding of full software development life cycle and modernization of legacy applications.

Experience



Technical Consultant

FORCAM

Jun 2019 - Present (2 years 1 month +)

- Implementation and configuration of the software product FORCAM FORCE ™ to meet customer requirements (incl. creation of customer-specific Reports, Visualizations & Dashboards)
- Documenting technical architecture and creation of global template for specific project needs
- Liaise with the Project manager and Product owner to incorporate change requests and new features within the company product
- Integration of third-party systems with FORCAM Bridge API
- Second level support for In-Production systems
- Support testing/maintenance of several functionalities during product development

Dbyd Field Interviewer

Information By Design (IBYD)

Dec 2018 - May 2019 (6 months)

- Carry out in-person surveys all around Nottinghamshire on behalf of Nottingham City Council
- Work with colleagues and a line manager to meet quotas including age group and gender
- Ensure that the information is recorded in line with Market Research Society's Code of Conduct

Network Engineer

Jindal Electro Systems

Jan 2018 - Jul 2018 (7 months)

- Research and implement CCTV security and GPS tracking systems
- Support on-site technicians during hardware installation and equipment set-up
- Troubleshoot & resolve network, hardware, and software issues



Android/Web Developer

Freelance

Jul 2013 - Jun 2018 (5 years)

- Create high-quality responsive web layouts by following HTML/CSS best practices
- Build and release production quality native and hybrid apps on mobile application stores
- Write efficient and testable backend code using market-tested tools and practices

- Support post-development life cycle through bug-fixing and maintenance releases

IT Specialist

Jayess Builders Mar 2017 - Nov 2017 (9 months)

PHP Programmer

Freelance Jul 2012 - Jun 2013 (1 year)

Education

Nottingham Trent University

Master of Science - MS, Cloud Computing 2018 - 2020

Nottingham Trent University

Diploma in Professional Practice 2019 - 2020

RIMT University

Bachelor of Technology - BTech, Computer Science 2008 - 2012

Licenses & Certifications

- IBM Certified Associate Developer Rational Application Developer V8 IBM
- International English Language Testing System (IELTS) IDP Education Ltd

Skills

Technical Architecture • Java • Microsoft Azure • Android • SQL • Linux • Software as a Service (SaaS) • Docker Products • Node.js • Node-RED

Honors & Awards

University of the Year Scholarship - Nottingham Trent University

Mar 2019